IKAWA
(井川)
Wow, we're really driving dangerously.
真是行驶在一个很不得了的地方呢
We're completely on the edge of the cliff.
完全在悬崖边上
Hey, Miss, are you alone?
我说 小妹妹 你是自己来旅行吗
Want to share some snacks?
要一起吃点心吗
Can I?
可以吗
POTATO CRISPS
(薯片)
Try some of mine too.
那也尝尝我带的吧
LAID-BACK CAMP SEASON 3
《摇曳露营△ (第三季)》
EPISODE 4: JOURNEY TO HATANAGI AND THE ROAD TO HELL
(第4话 前往畑薙 地狱的死亡之路)
So you guys came from Mie?
大姐姐们是从三重来的啊
We're headed to a hidden gem in Oshizu.
我们打算去奥静的秘境
We had planned to wait until early April when the cherry blossoms are in full bloom,
本来是想等4月初 樱花盛开后再来的
but this one here hates crowds,
但这个人说她讨厌人挤人
so we decided to come this week instead.
就选在这礼拜过来了
If everyone's there, it's no more a hidden gem, no?
毕竟人一多 就没有秘境的感觉了呀
Where are you getting off?
小妹妹要在哪一站下车呀?
We're going all the way to the end, Ikawa.
我们会一路搭到终点站井川
I'll be getting off at a place called Abt-Ichishiro Station
我要在一个叫ABT市代站的地方下车
and then walking to the nearby campsite.
再走去那附近的露营场
Are you going camping?
你要去露营啊
We tried camping near our hometown
我们1月的时候为了跟风
in January, just to follow the trend.
也有去老家附近露营过呢
Yeah.
是啊
We forgot the fuel for the heater and almost froze to death.
当时忘记带暖炉的灯油 差点就死在那边了
When you come to Mie for a visit,
哪天小妹妹来三重玩时
you should check it out.
也可以去看看哦
Even though that campsite is at the tip of Shima,
虽然那个露营地在志摩的尖端
it's a great spot.
不过是个好地方
The tip of Shima.
志摩的尖端
The campsite at the tip of Rin (Shima).
在小凛的尖端的露营场
Approaching Abt-Ichishiro Station.
即将抵达ABT市代站
We're here.
到了
Well then, this is my stop.
那我先告辞了
Aren't you going to stay for the linking?
小妹妹不看完合体再走吗
Linking?
合体?
The road up ahead is steep,
因为接下来的线路要爬陡坡
so, they're going to attach a ABT rack rail train here.
得在这边装上ABT式机关车
I'm here.
我来了
Hello.
拜托了
-It'll push the whole train -We got this!
-然后它就会在后面用力地 -加油
-from behind.
-把整台车推上去哦
It's said that underneath its carriage, there are gears installed,
据说它的车体下方装有齿轮
allowing it to climb upward using the force
因此能利用齿轮 与齿轨啮合的力量往上爬
Linking.
合体
Apparently, you can only witness this here in all of Japan.
听说全日本只有这里 可以看到这个景象
Train enthusiasts must be thrilled.
铁道迷要嗨翻了啊
But you're not a train enthusiast.
你又不是什么铁道迷
You take care of yourself, Miss.
那么 小妹妹要注意安全哦
You guys too.
大姐姐们也是
WATCH OUT FOR ONCOMING TRAINS
(小心来车)
Amusing ladies, those two.
那两个大姐姐真风趣呢
Let's see. To get to the campsite…
我看看哦 露营场在…
GO STRAIGHT THROUGH THE TUNNEL
(通过隧道即可抵达)
This way.
好像在这里
That's a huge suspension bridge!
好大的吊桥
I wonder if Rin and Aya passed by here?
小凛她们是不是也有到这里来呢
All right. Let's check in at the campsite first
呃 等等先去露营场办理入住
and get us a good spot.
然后占个好地方
"ABT-ICHISHIRO STATION" After I put away my luggage,
(ABT市代站) 把行李放好后
"CAMPSITE" I'll walk to Nagashima Dam Station
(露营场) 走路到长岛水坝站
"NAGASHIMA DAM STATION" and take the train to Okuoikojo Station.
(长岛水坝站) 接着再搭电车到奥大井湖上站
The next train from Nagashima Dam Station departs at 14:32.
长岛水坝站的下一班电车 是14点32分发车
Just over an hour left until the next train.
离下一班车 只剩1小时再多一点点的时间了
I better hurry!
加紧赶路吧
"Go straight through the tunnel", as in…
"通过隧道即可抵达"的意思是…
Must… Must I go through this tunnel
不…不走这里的话
to get to the campsite?
就不能到露营场吗
Bats!
有蝙蝠
Can't see the light at the end of the tunnel at all…
完全看不到尽头在哪里
Just how long is this tunnel?
这个隧道到底多长啊
This is the time to clear your mind.
这种时候就要把脑袋放空
This is just an ordinary tunnel…
这个只是普通的隧道
Just keep walking straight, and you'll get out of here.
只要一直往前走 就能走出去了
Finally, I can see the exit!
终于看到出口了
This is actually the old track of the discontinued ABT railway line.
这里其实是已经废线的 ABT式铁道的旧线路
Now, it's called the "Obake Tunnel".
现在改为"妖怪隧道"
Many locals display decorations of spirits and monsters
摆有许多在地人自制的妖怪装饰
to scare visitors.
吓唬那些来访的游客
Check-out time is 11 AM.
退宿时间是11点
If you need to leave early in the morning,
如果一大早就要离开
just drop the guidebook into the mailbox.
请直接将露营手册投进信箱里
Are you okay, young lady?
小姑娘 你没事吧?
After calming down
平复一下心情
and storing her luggage, it's time to choose a camping spot.
寄放好行李后 开始选营位
Where should we choose?
要把帐篷搭在哪里呢
Spot secured.
占好位置了
I'VE SECURED THE SPOT. NOW, I'M GOING TO CHECK OUT THE "EGG".
(我占好位置了) (接下来要去看蛋)
40 minutes until the train leaves!
离电车发车还有40分
THIS WAY TO CAMP ICHISHIRO
(市代露营场在前方)
Let's see…
我看看哦
Nagashima Dam.
长岛水坝
It's ginormous!
好大哦
So, based on the dam curry,
用水坝咖喱饭来打比方的话
that suspension bridge is the fried shrimp.
那座吊桥就是炸虾
I'm the fried shrimp.
我是炸虾
That dam's the rice.
那个水坝则是大碗白饭
I'm the rice.
我是白饭
And the other side of the dam
然后那个水坝的另一侧
is filled with curry!
就是满满的咖喱酱
The area around the dam looks just like the mortar and pestle.
水坝的周围正好是擂钵状
Reminds me of Mount Omuro.
让人不禁想起大室山的景色呢
MOUNT OMURO
(大室山)
MINISTRY OF LAND, INFRASTRUCTURE, TRANSPORT AND TOURISM
(国土交通省)
Never mind.
放弃
THE DREAMS NURTURED BY WATER AND THE BEAUTY OF GREENERY AND NATURE
(水所孕育的梦与绿意与自然之美) (长岛水坝)
So high!
好高
It's amazing how humans can build such enormous structures.
居然能盖出这么大的东西 人类还真厉害啊
Ah! The train's here!
呃 电车已经来了
Wait for me!
我要搭…
Barely made it…
勉强赶上了
If I had gotten off here,
要是刚才在这里下车
I probably wouldn't have had to go through that tunnel.
或许就不用走那个可怕的隧道了吧
Thank you for your patience.
让各位乘客久等了
This train is about to depart.
本次列车即将发车
The next stop is Hiranda Station.
下一站是平田站 平田站
Off to Okuoikojo Station! Destination, boiled egg!
前往奥大井湖上站 目标是看水煮蛋
LAKE IKAWA
(井川湖)
That was an awful ride!
真的有够难骑
As dangerous as that road was,
虽然刚才那里挺惊险的
I couldn't help but laugh.
但我还是忍不住笑出来了
After making those twists and turns with confidence…
气势十足地骑过弯道后
Hello!
哈啰…
That was really risky.
真的超危险
I can just about keep up only because I ride regularly. Thank goodness.
幸亏我平时也有在骑车 才能勉强反应过来
Reminds me of those slippery road signs.
当时我瞬间想起那个 "小心路滑"的标志
It's been a bumpy ride
过了接岨湖后
since Lake Sesso.
路况好像变得很不好呢
It definitely lives up to its moniker, "the road to hell".
难怪会被称作"险道"
That'll be 319 yen for 2.2 litres.
2.2升的汽油 总共319圆
Here's 320 yen.
好的 给你320圆
Text from Nadeshiko.
是抚子传来的
I'VE SECURED THE SPOT. NOW, I'M GOING TO CHECK OUT THE "EGG".
(我占好位置了) (接下来要去看蛋)
What's that emoji supposed to mean?
这是什么啊?
An egg?
是蛋吗
Looks like she got there safely. Good to know.
看来她顺利抵达了 太好了
Nadeshiko's all grown up now.
抚子变坚强了呢
Nothing. Nothing at all.
没事 没什么
All right. We should be on our way to Hatanagi.
那么 我们也该前往畑薙了
Ikawa Bridge.
井川大桥
Is this the suspension bridge you mentioned we could bike across?
你早上说可以把车骑上去的吊桥 就是这座吗
Yep.
没错…
The scenery here is lovely.
这里的风景也很不错呢
The lake's a beautiful green colour.
湖水还是漂亮的碧绿色
It's so peaceful here.
真宁静呢
This "road to hell" is longer and tougher than I thought.
这条死亡之路 比想象中还漫长又坎坷呢
"Road to hell"?
什么死亡之路啊
We've got a ways to go before we reach Hatanagi.
而且畑薙离这里还有一段距离呢
I'm hungry, Rin. Why don't we get something to eat first?
小凛 我肚子饿了 先去吃点午餐吧
Before we set out, you said…
出发的时候
To make dinner even tastier,
为了让晚餐变得更美味
let's skip lunch.
中午就别吃了
After all, an empty stomach is the best seasoning, right?
毕竟空腹就是最棒的调味料呀
Didn't you?
你不是这么说过吗
Did I?
有吗
I'm tired.
好累哦
Well, I don't mind either way.
罢了 我是都可以啦
But are there places that sell food nearby?
但这附近有餐厅吗
I think I remember seeing one near the petrol station.
加油站附近倒是好像有一间
About that, I checked on my phone and found a nice place.
其实我刚才用手机查过 正好发现了一家店
The oden is hot and yummy!
关东煮热乎乎的真好吃
This is what they call, "starting a fire and then putting it out."
这就是所谓的先放火再救火啊
What fire?
什么先救火?
N… No, it's nothing.
没…没事 没什么
Here's some tea for you girls.
来 请喝茶
Thank you.
谢谢
Where are you two from?
两位小姐是从哪里来的呀?
I'm from Hamamatsu.
我是从滨松来的
You certainly drove a long way.
居然从那么远的地方过来
That's impressive.
你真厉害呢
I'm from Minobu.
我是从身延来的
It's right next to Yamanashi, but that's still quite the distance,
山梨虽然就在隔壁 但也很远呢
given all the mountain roads.
毕竟这附近有很多山
But I've gone through the Yamabushi Pass to get to Kofu from Hayakawa myself.
不过我以前也会走山伏峠 从早川到甲府去呢
You mean the road that goes through Amehata?
难道您是走那条会经过雨畑的路吗
That's right.
没错
Amehata?
雨畑?
Yamanashi has a road called Amehata Forest Road
山梨有一条能直通井川 名叫雨畑林道的道路
I went there at the end of January.
我1月底的时候还去了一趟呢
But now it's closed, so we can't use it anymore.
但现在因为禁止通行 所以不能走了
When did you drive there?
您是几年前去的呢?
Let me think.
我想想哦
It was when I was still taking care of my children.
因为是我还在带孩子的时候
It must have been about 30 years ago.
大约是30年前的事了吧
30 years?
30年
They probably didn't have the money to repair the road.
我想肯定是没钱整修道路吧
ODEN
(关东煮)
BEER, SNACKS, GROCERIES, OPEN FOR BUSINESS
(啤酒 点心 杂货 营业中)
Thank you for your hospitality.
多谢款待
Thank you, ladies.
两位小姐 谢谢你们哦
Not only was the oden delicious,
不仅关东煮很好吃
but we also got to hear some interesting tales of the past.
还听到有趣的陈年往事 真是来对了
The mountaintop is covered in snow.
山顶上一片白雪皑皑啊
The altitude is higher up there.
毕竟那边的海拔比较高
It's probably going to get even colder.
等等应该会变得更冷吧
How far is it from here to Lake Hatanagi?
这里离畑薙湖还有多远啊?
Let me check.
我看看哦
Those guided by Guruguru Map
受咕噜咕噜地图指引的人们啊
should pass through the scattered seven Tashiros
去穿过散落于世间的七个田代吧
to reach the legendary lake.
这样就能抵达传说之湖
Why are you speaking like an RPG character?
为什么变成RPG风啊
And what are those "Tashiros"?
是说那个"田代"又是什么啊
Guruguru Map sometimes leads you through strange paths.
咕噜咕噜地图有时候 都会带人走奇怪的路呢
I know that well.
我懂
TASHIRO TUNNEL 1, 500M
(田代第1隧道 长500米)
So the "Tashiros" refer to the Tashiro Tunnels.
原来"田代"指的是田代隧道啊
Correct.
没错…
One.
一
Two.
二
Three.
三
Four.
四
Five.
五
Six.
六
Seven.
七
Hatanagi.
畑薙
This route has a total of seven Tashiro Tunnels.
这条路上总共有七个田代隧道
Pass through all of them
只要通过所有隧道
and we'll arrive at Lake Hatanagi.
就会抵达畑薙湖了
I see.
原来如此
Off we go, then!
那我们就出发吧
Okay.
好
TASHIRO TUNNEL 2, 85M
(田代第2隧道 长85米)
TASHIRO TUNNEL 3, 7M
(田代第3隧道 长7米)
TASHIRO TUNNEL 4, 63M
(田代第4隧道 长63米)
TASHIRO TUNNEL 5, 35M
(田代第5隧道 长35米)
TASHIRO TUNNEL 6, 37M
(田代第6隧道 长37米)
TASHIRO TUNNEL 7, 161M
(田代第7隧道 长161米)
From Senzu, the girls drove for about 45 kilometres.
从千头出发后 大约骑了45公里
Rin.
小凛
Arrived at Lake Hatanagi.
抵达畑薙湖
Finally here!
终于到了
I can't go any further…
已经骑不动了
This isn't the kind of place you can just come to casually.
这不是一个能随随便便 说来就来的地方啊
I'm really sorry for inviting you to drive here carelessly.
随随便便邀你来这种地方 真的很抱歉
We made it at last.
终于到了呢
Yeah.
是啊
The Hatanagi Suspension Bridge should be a little further ahead.
再往前走应该有座畑薙吊桥吧
But they put up a sign.
但那里放了禁止通行的栅栏
I don't think we can drive directly there.
应该不能骑机车进去吧
Come on. Let's go to the suspension bridge.
走吧 去吊桥那里
What?
什么
It took so much effort to get here. Forget about the suspension bridge.
好不容易才骑到这里 吊桥就算了吧
It's another 5KM walk from here back and forth.
来回好像要走个5公里耶
No way! We've come this far.
不…正因为好不容易才到这里
It would be a waste not to go check it out!
不过去看看 才是亏大了啊
I think you've totally lost it…
你这是进入破罐破摔的状态了吧
Think about it.
你仔细想想
If you change your mind and want to check out that bridge next time,
如果以后想去畑薙的吊桥走走
you'll have to go through that hellish road again.
就又要经过那段地狱的死亡之路哦
Well… you do have a point…
话…话是这么说没错啦
Fine! I'll go! I'll do it!
好啦 我走 我走就是了
So, this is the deepest of Shizuoka reachable by bike, huh?
这里就是骑机车能到的 静冈最深处吗
To the suspension bridge? That's quite far from here.
你们要去吊桥吗 那里还挺远的哦
And the roads aren't exactly in the best condition. Are you sure?
而且路况也很糟糕 真的没问题吗
It's not too far of a walk.
反正也没有远到走不过去
We'll manage.
没问题的
ACCESS PROHIBITED
(全面禁止通行)
Be careful.
路上小心哦
Let me know when you're back.
回来后记得和我说一声
Got it.
知道了
We've come all this way through that hellish road.
我们可是一路从凶险的道路 颠簸过来的呢
Little late for warnings, huh?
这个提醒未免来得太迟了吧
The road conditions are even worse than before.
比刚才的路况还糟糕
It's all muddy everywhere.
到处都是烂泥啊
When he said it isn't in the best condition, he means these puddles and mud, huh?
原来他的不好走 是指路上会有这些水坑泥泞吗
Guess we'll have to tread carefully…
看来只能小心脚下
…and push through.
硬着头皮走过去了呢
So, your grandpa used to ride a motorcycle, too?
原来小绫的爷爷也会骑机车啊
He stopped since he got a bad back.
虽然现在因为腰痛 已经不能骑了
When I was little, I'd sit behind him, and he'd drive me around.
但我小时候经常坐在后坐 跟他一起去兜风
Your grandpa drives a bike too, right?
小凛的爷爷也会骑机车吧
That makes us
那我们两个
"GRANDDAUGHTER RIDERS" the "granddaughter riders"!
(孙女骑士) 就是孙女骑士了呢
Hey!
你好
The heck is that?
那是什么啊
I couldn't find any girls around me who ride motorcycles,
因为我身边完全找不到 会骑机车的女孩子
so meeting a fellow rider like you really makes me happy.
能交到像小凛这样的车友 真的让我很开心哦
That's why you chose such a dangerous route for our first trip?
所以第一次骑行就挑了 这么危险的路吗
Well, I like biking.
因为我很喜欢骑车嘛
I wanted to challenge all kinds of roads.
所以才想骑骑看各种各样的道路
You know, there are many girls in Yamanashi who ride motorcycles to school.
山梨有满多女孩子会骑机车上学哦
Oh, really?
这样啊
Is that the suspension bridge we're looking for?
那个就是我们要找的吊桥吧
It looks like it,
确实长得有点像
but it seems like there's still some way to go.
看起来还有段距离呢
Yeah.
是啊
Hatanagi Suspension Bridge.
畑薙大吊桥
HATANAGI SUSPENSION BRIDGE MAXIMUM CAPACITY: 15 PEOPLE
(畑薙大吊桥 最多乘载15人 过桥时请小心一点)
The footing is so narrow!
能踩的地方好窄
And the railing is thin!
扶手也好细
And it's super high!
而且超高的
Approximately 30 metres above ground.
高度约30米
Well, we've come this far.
反…反正都走到这里了
I think we can turn back now.
差不多可以回去了吧
You're the one who insisted we come to this bridge!
说要去吊桥上走走的不是小凛你吗
I have serious concerns about this…
不…不妙啊
It's only secured with steel wires,
因为它只用钢丝去固定踏板
and it creaks with every step. Feels like it could come loose any moment.
每走一步就会发出喀啦喀啦的声音 感觉随时都可能松脱
And being deep in the mountains,
再加上还是深山里的吊桥
I doubt it gets much maintenance.
肯定没办法保养得很细致
It makes you wonder if a screw might suddenly
让人忍不住胡思乱想
come loose or something.
螺丝会不会突然脱落什么的
You know how some people accidentally drop their phones
有…有些人不是会为了 在这种地方拍网美照
while taking aesthetic photos in places like this?
结果不小心弄掉手机吗
Yeah, instead of worrying about dropping a phone,
比…比起担心手机掉下去
I think we should be more concerned about not losing our lives here.
我觉得更应该小心 别在这里丢了小命
Absolutely.
没错
Ri… Rin,
小…小凛
I'm still really scared. I think we should cross one at a time.
我还是觉得很害怕 我们一个一个过去吧
B-but we're already halfway across.
可…可是我们都已经走到一半了
If we both go together, what if the bridge collapses…?
两个人走的话 万一桥掉下去…
It… It's shaking!
等等 好晃
The bridge keeps swaying!
桥一直在晃啊
One way or another, they made it to the other side.
总算来到对面了
Beyond here is the mountain trail.
再往前走就是登山步道了
The brave ones will continue forward.
勇士们还会继续往前进呢
BEWARE OF BEARS
(小心熊出没)
Let's head back.
回去吧
Right this instant.
马上回去吧
Don't shake, Rin!
小凛 你不要乱晃哦
That's my line!
你才不要乱晃啊
OKUOI KOZYO
(奥大井湖上)
IKAWA
(井川)
RAINBOW BRIDGE KOZYO TRAIL
(彩虹桥 湖上步道)
Okuoikojo Station.
奥大井湖上站
It's amazing that they actually built a station in such a location.
这个车站真的建在一个 很厉害的地方耶
That must be the boiled egg in the dam curry.
用水坝咖喱饭来打比方 那就是水煮蛋的部分呢
Speaking of which,
话说回来
the men taking photos here
在这边拍照的叔叔们
are using some pretty high-end cameras.
都用很高档的相机呢
So, those beautiful pictures we see online
原来网络上那些漂亮的照片
are taken like this, huh?
都是这样拍出来的呀
I'll join in
那我也一起来
and take a panoramic shot too.
拍张全景照
Perfect.
很好
HATANAGI VILLAGE OPEN
(畑薙庄 营业中)
Soaking my chilled body in the hot spring is the best.
把冰凉的身体泡在温泉里 感觉超赞的
The best…
超赞的…
The wonderful warmth is just fantastic.
这绝妙的温热感实在太棒了
I actually prefer it a bit hotter.
我倒是喜欢再热一点呢
The texture of the water is so smooth, and it's just the right temperature,
因为泉质很滑溜 水也温温的
making it a warm and silky hot spring.
所以是温温滑滑温泉呢
Even if I were to melt in this water, I wouldn't have any regrets.
就算要我融化在这水中 我也没有什么遗憾啦
About to melt away, huh?
要融化啦
I just thought of your expression when we were crossing the bridge.
想起小绫在过桥时的表情了
As if you were any better.
你不也是这种表情吗
Although it was tiring and scary,
虽然又累又可怕
reaching the suspension bridge was really great.
但有走到吊桥那里 真是太好了呢
Yeah, it's good we made it.
嗯 幸好有走过去
34 kilometres back to the campsite.
距离露营场还有34公里
I don't want to drive back!
好懒得回去
We're heading to the campsite now.
我们现在要过去露营场了
We'll be driving from Hatanagi.
要从畑薙回去你那边啦
It'll take about two hours.
不过大概要花2小时左右
Roger that. Drive safely.
知道了 路上小心哦
Okay.
好
Two hours, huh? Sounds tough.
2小时啊 感觉很辛苦呢
I guess I'll take it easy
那我就先她们一步回到露营场
and head back to the campsite first.
悠哉地打发时间吧
NEXT EPISODE: BONFIRE AND BEEF FEAST
(下集 篝火和牛肉盛宴)
WHEN ENJOYING CAMPING, BE SURE TO FOLLOW THE RULES
(享受露营时…) (务必遵守露营场和其设施的规定)
DON'T FORGET TO PUT OUT YOUR CAMPFIRE AND DISPOSE OF YOUR GARBAGE.
(别忘了灭火和带走垃圾)
TEMPERATURES CAN CHANGE QUICKLY, SO CHECK THE WEATHER FORECAST BEFOREHAND.
(由于气温可能会急速变化) (记得事先确认天气预报)
WEAR WARM CLOTHING IF NECESSARY TO PREVENT COLD.
(必要时穿着保暖衣物防寒)